3 days of peace, music...and love.
Woodstock is a documentary, history, music film directed by Michael Wadleigh.
An intimate look at the Woodstock Music & Art Festival held in Bethel, NY in 1969, from preparation through cleanup, with historic access to insiders, blistering concert footage, and portraits of the concertgoers; negative and positive aspects are shown,
from drug use by performers to naked fans sliding in the mud, from the collapse of the fences by the unexpected hordes to the surreal arrival of National Guard helicopters with food and medical assistance for the impromptu city of 500,000.
Self, played by Richie Havens.
Self, played by Joan Baez.
Self - The Who, played by Roger Daltrey.
Self - The Who, played by John Entwistle.
Self - The Who, played by Keith Moon.
Self - The Who, played by Pete Townshend.
Woodstock is a 1970 American documentary film of the watershed counterculture
Woodstock Festival which took place in August 1969 near Bethel, New York.
The film was directed by Michael Wadleigh in his directorial debut.
Seven editors are credited, including Thelma
Schoonmaker, Martin Scorsese, and Wadleigh.
Woodstock was a great commercial and critical success.
It received the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature.
Schoonmaker was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Film
Editing, a rare distinction for a documentary.
Dan Wallin and L.
Johnson were nominated for the Academy Award for Best Sound.
The film was screened at the 1970 Cannes Film Festival, but
was not entered into the main competition.
The 1970 theatrical release of the film ran 185 minutes.
A director's cut spanning 224 minutes was released in 1994.
Both cuts take liberties with the timeline of the festival.
However, the opening and closing acts are the same in the film as they appeared on
stage; Richie Havens opens the show and Jimi Hendrix closes it.
In 1996, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
An expanded 40th Anniversary Edition of Woodstock, released on June 9, 2009, in Blu-ray and DVD formats, features additional performances not
before seen in the film, and it includes lengthened versions of existing performances, such as Creedence Clearwater Revival.
The film explores themes of hippie, free love,
music festival, marijuana, rock music.
The tone is uplifting and mind_bending.